AJIBOLA UMARHABIB CSM²⁰²⁰

Product / Program Manager

Ajibola4000@gmail.com | 818-312-8803 | www.linkedin.com/in/ajibola-umarhabib-tech

SUMMARY

A cross functional solution-driven, value oriented manager with immense creativity, high business acumen, and team friendliness having emphasis working with cross functional global teams with over 6 years of experience catering to a diverse industry delivering product and SaaS solutions through consultative sales, project management, business analysis, and customer relationship management (CRM) expertise with a natural ability to conceptualize (start-finish), implement, manage and grow business programs with established KPI's, mitigated risks and adaptability to change (PMP Trained with emphasis on AGILE-Scrum environments & Data Privacy Compliant).

PROGRAM
MANAGEMENT
EXPERIENCE/
HIGHLIGHTS

Zander Mercy: Mercy Nation Ambassador Program (Micro-Influencer Marketing)

 Proposed and launched the company's first Micro-Influencer Marketing Program dubbed "Mercy Nation" which accounts for 90% of the company's sales (2020)

Energon Corp: Energon Royalty, Customer Reward Program (Managed by Energon Royalty Team)

• Energon Royalty was a reward program that rewarded customers for patronizing Energon's services through discounts, rewards, cash back, and referral checks.

Rekun Tech: LEC Dream Event, Product Owner + xFAQs Product Owner (design, implementation, & growth)

• Designed and Launched web app to take customer requirements, present available dates at the event center, and offer an event estimate (2016)

Magnaquest Tech: Product Manager: Sure CRM (Europe, Middle East & Africa–EMEA)

 As product manager of SURE CRM, EMEA, worked with Senior Vice President of Sales to design, propose and co-launch the "CapEx vs OpEx Sales Program" for developing countries (2014)

WORK EXPERIENCE 2019 - 2020

ZANDER MERCY

A beauty and cosmetic company specializing in delivering market focused products and brands to consumers. Zander Mercy is a global company bringing affordable top of the line products to the masses.

*Program Manager: Mercy Nation Ambassador Program, USA** (08/19 to Date)

- Designed and launched Mercy Nation which was a micro-influencer marketing program on major social media networks (eg. Instagram and YouTube)
 - Accounts for 90% of Digital Marketing Sales
 - Growing network of 20 influencer and counting
 - Influencer performance measured by reach, engagement and conversion and referral codes
- Designed the marketing and distribution roadmaps for beauty products released and unreleased
- Compiled and funneled marketing data into company's ZoHo CRM customer retention & growth campaigns as CRM Administrator (Big Data Management).
- Organizing market research activities such as Data sampling, AB Testing, and survey analysis to prioritize product release schedules and "key marketable ingredients"
- Works with teams on planning, designing, packaging, labeling of periodic releases and to ensure all releasable products are brand compliant through hands on quality control mechanisms

ENERGON CORP

2017 - 2019

A home utility management company offering Smart Energy &Water solution products & services to homeowners. Energon Corp operated in an AGILE – SCRUM friendly environment where I served as a cross functional executive as the company's a program manager, tech administrator, sales director and Senior Operation Officer.

Program Manager: Energon Royalty, USA

(03/17 to 06/19)

- Designed and Launched Energon Royalty a sales and marketing program:
 - The flagship sales-team offering the program outperformed all other sales-team at the time.
 - Trained internal team on program offerings and approach to market.
 - Increased closing rate by a 20% closing margin.
 - Designed & implemented an Agile & CRM compliant cross-department project management system using Trello Boards, with push-to-board & email functions along with detail board manuals.

- Designed and implemented a new recruit activation program which increased new recruit performance, productivity & retention and reduced recruit's activation time from 60 to 7 days.
- Generated team performance reports by running analytics on weekly sales & sale projections
 Offering training and support on tech infrastructure and its user-ability across departments,
 which were used to set and assess Key Performance Index (KPI's)
- Oversaw solar project sales/delivery and managed team at Energon to produce a weekly average of \$120,000 of weekly sales volume. (sales, design, implementation, quality control and monitoring)
- Gathered homeowner requirements, business risks and managed pre-sale and post-sales activities
- Served as CRM integrator managing, analyzing, & coordinating big data (client/partner/vendors) across SetMore, Trello, Spotio, Spreadsheet, & HubSpot CRM.
- Supply chain management procuring project material based on requirements on-demand.
- Responsible for managing and adapting go-to-market strategies, work-flows and resources to
 drive team sales (instrumental in the company's fast-paced revolving-product based marketing
 campaign strategy in both CRM marketing and Field Marketing)
- Continual lead generation: nurturing, qualifying, & analysis to maintain and support sales pipeline.
- Monitoring & managing project workflows of solar installations and secondary-service-delivery
 at all customer sites using tech solutions like ZoHo CRMs, HubSpot, and Salesforce as well as
 Trello and other cloud services.

REKUN TECHNOLOGIES

A tech consulting firm charged with the Management of large business portfolios with cross-industry business assets where I served as a cross functional account manager, solutions architect and project manager (Tech, Real Estate, & Hospitality).

Account Manager & Solution Architect

(4/15 to 3/16)

- Product Owner / Program Manager of LEC Dream Events: Designed and Launched web app to take customer requirements, present available dates at the event center, and offer an event estimate (2016)
- *Product Owner, xFAQs:* Managed & designed business plan, roadmap, & service offerings for SaaS prototype (xFAQs) and worked with DevOps to develop working software
- Provided cross training on all solutions being delivered to client's internal team, complete with guide notes to comply with change management standard
- Gathered intelligence on client's business processes, standards of operations, and identified project requirements and risks to meet client's growth / system needs
- Designed, integrated and trained staff on workflow / sales processes streamlined using scheduling System, QuickBooks and ZoHo CRM for LEC
- Oversaw system migration from Sales Force to ZoHo CRM for LEC & Rekun Tech RBD
- Tripled sales volume of event space within 3 three months through the design and implementation of new growth strategy. (LEC)
- Developed and implemented a business enhancement and sustainability plan for LEC to drive growth & managed resources to support other business activities
- Maintained overview and trained staff on compliance of processes, production quality, and distinguished professionalism for LEC, Rekun, & xFAQs.

MAGNAQUEST TECHNOLOGIES LTD

A multinational tech service provider offering turn-key CRM and Business solutions for Utilities, Internet Service Providers (ISPs), Telcos, and Cable Companies. Served as a cross functional Product Manager and Regional Sales Representative & Account Manager for SURE CRM, EMEA.

Product Manager: SURE CRM, EMEA

(5/14 to 4/15)

- Tasked with ensuring product integrity & sales within region
- worked with Senior Vice President of Sales to design, propose and co-launch *the "CapEx vs OpEx Sales Program"* for developing countries (2014)
- Oversaw the implementation of Sure CRM, liaising with local clients and technical teams.
- Gathered intelligence on client's business processes, standards of operations, and identified project requirements and risks to meet client's growth / system needs
- Conducted presales, post-sales and sales performance activities
- Conducted sales engagement campaigns specifically tailored towards individual prospects, via SUGAR CRM & presented consultative sales presentations & scheduled product demos

2015 - 2016

2014 - 2015

CALEB UNIVERSITY

BSc. Hons BIOCHEMISTRY (+ Entrepreneurial Studies)

2013

EDUCATION/ CERTIFICATIONS: 2013 - DATE

TECHNICAL TOOLS

EXTERNAL PROJECT MANAGEMENT TRAININGS & CERTIFICATIONS

New Horizon: PMI Project Management Training (Waterfall)
 LinkedIn: PMI-ACP Training (emphasis on Scrum)

• Scrum Alliance: Certified Scrum Master

2020

In Progress:

Certified CRM Admin // MySQL // AWS Cloud Architect Training // Certified Scrum Project Manager

Work Environments: MSOS/iOS / Cloud / VS Friendly/ AGILE & SCRUM Friendly

CRM & ERPs: Salesforce, MS Dynamic 365, ZoHo, Sugar, Sure, Prosper Works, etc.

Account/Compliance: QuickBooks, ADP Tally, DocuSign, Adobe, Peach Tree, POS, Turbo Tax etc.

Productivity: Jira, Trello, Asana, MS Project, & Office 365, Outlook, SharePoint.

Creativity: Adobe Photoshop, Corel Draw, Flier builders etc.

TECH & HEALTH ECOSYSTEM PARTICIPANT

Rotary, Blacks in Tech, ITMT, SOGF, Freedom Foundation etc.

Board Member Blacks United in Leading Technology International (2020)

- Community Advisory board member *ITMT Men's Health Group* (2018)
- Tech Volunteer, Hackathon participant / supervisor at Tech programs since 2013
- Offering Start Up Mentoring services with non-profit empowerment centers

MEMBERSHIPS/ SOCIAL ENGAGEMENT 2013 - DATE